RG 004:028, Colchester Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Colchester Probate Court records
1721-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Colchester District)
45.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1741-1976; Probate files, 1721-1920
RG004_028
1912-003 and 2011-103
Historical Note
Colchester, New London County, Town established in 1698
The Colchester Probate District was constituted May 29, 1832, from the East Haddam Probate District. It served the municipality of Colchester and also the municipality of Marlborough from May 29, 1832 to June 11, 1846, and the part of Salem taken from Colchester from May 29, 1832 to July 9, 1841. The Colchester Probate District merged with the Eastford (part), Hampton, and Windham Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Windham - Colchester Probate District, which serves the municipalities of Chaplin, Colchester, Hampton, Lebanon, Scotland, and Windham.
Town of Colchester, Probate District chronology:
1698 - October 1708, New London County Court and District
October 1708 - October 1741, Hartford District
October 1741 - May 28, 1832, East Haddam District
May 29, 1832 - January 4, 2011, Colchester District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Windham - Colchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes, 1-37, 1741-1976. Volumes 1-9 and part of Volume 10 contain records for the East Haddam Probate District which held the court in Colchester. When the Colchester Probate District was established in 1832, recordkeeping continued in the same Volume 10 and subsequent volumes continued the numbering sequence. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1721-1920. Probate files dated from 1721 to May 28, 1832 are for the East Haddam Probate District that held court in Colchester. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1721-1920 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 37. There are 3 volumes of bonds that are unnumbered.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-003 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Colchester; Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Haddam; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Marlborough; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Salem
Places:
Colchester (Conn.); East Haddam (Conn.); Marlborough (Conn.); Salem (Conn.)
Alternate Creator:
Connecticut. Probate Court (East Haddam District)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-103, Record books, 1741-1976, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-14 (there are 2 volumes numbered 13), 17-18, 22, 1741-1922; probate files 1721-1920 (Accession 1912-003); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): August 12, 1912 (1721-1890); June 16, 1930 (1856-1909); January 23, 1940 (1908-1920). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-103 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 19, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1741-1976; 19.5 cubic feet (40 volumes); 2011-103
  - Records, 1741-1747 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1747-1759 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1759-1771 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1772-1784 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1780-1790 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1790-1803 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1803-1816 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1816-1824 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1824-1829 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1829-1839 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1840-1851 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1850-1864 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1864-1877 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1877-1886 (Volume 14)
  - Orders and decrees, 1883-1885 (Volume 15)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Orders and decrees, 1885-1892 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1886-1892 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1892-1904 (Volume 18)
  - Orders and decrees, 1895-1905 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1904-1922 (Volume 20)
  - Orders and decrees, 1905-1913 (Volume 21)
  - Orders and decrees, 1913-1915 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1922-1934 (Volume 23)
  - Orders and decrees, 1925-1934 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1934-1942 (Volumne 25)
  - Orders and decrees, 1934-1942 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1942-1949 (Volume 27)
  - Orders and decrees, 1942-1950 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1949-1959 (Volume 29)
  - Orders and decrees, 1950-1957 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1959-1970 (Volume 31)
  - Orders and decrees, 1958-1963 (Volume 32)
  - Orders and decrees, 1963-1968 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1965-1969 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1966-1972 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1971-1974 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1973-1976 (Volume 37)
  - Bonds, 1881-1922, 1931 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1922-1962 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1962-1968 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1721-1920; 26 cubic feet; 1912-003
  - Abel - Allen (Drawer 1)
  - Almany - Atwell (Drawer 2)
  - Atwood - Ball (Drawer 3)
  - Ballard - Beebe, I. (Drawer 4)
  - Beebe, J. - Bigelow, H. (Drawer 5)
  - Bigelow, I. - Blish, G. (Drawer 6)
  - Blish, H. - Brainard, A. (Drawer 7)
  - Brainard, B. - Brainard, S. (Drawer 8)
  - Brainard, T. - Brown, G. (Drawer 9)
  - Brown, H. - Bulkeley, A. (Drawer 10)
  - Bulkeley, B. - Bulkeley, N. (Drawer 11)
  - Bulkeley, O. - Button (Drawer 12)
  - Calhoun - Carrier, Q. (Drawer 13)
  - Carrier, R. - Chamberlain, E. (Drawer 14)
  - Chamberlain, F. - Chapman, F. (Drawer 15)
  - Chapman, G. - Chapman, T. (Drawer 16)
  - Chapman, U. - Clark, E. (Drawer 17)
  - Clark F. - Coe (Drawer 18)
  - Coggshall - Cone, H. (Drawer 19)
  - Cone, I. - Connel (Drawer 20)
  - Conner - Crosby, I. (Drawer 21)
  - Crosby, J. - Daniels (Drawer 22)
  - Darbe - Dayton (Drawer 23)
  - Dean - Dodge, E. (Drawer 24)
  - Dodge, F. - Ely (Drawer 25)
  - Emmons - Fitch, L. (Drawer 26)
  - Fitch, M. - Foote, I. (Drawer 27)
  - Foote, J. - Fox, I. (Drawer 28)
  - Fox, J. - Fuller, R. (Drawer 29)
  - Fuller, S. - Gates, H. (Drawer 30)
  - Gates, I. - Gates, Z. (Drawer 31)
  - Gavit - Gillett, J. (Drawer 32)
  - Gillett, K. - Gosley (Drawer 33)
  - Gosling - Hale (Drawer 34)
  - Hall - Harris (Drawer 35)
  - Harvey - Hildreth (Drawer 36)
  - Hill - Horton (Drawer 37)
  - Hosford - Hungerford, J. (Drawer 38)
  - Hungerford, K. - Isham, J. (Drawer 39)
  - Isham, K. - Jones, J. (Drawer 40)
  - Jones, K. - Kellogg, C. (Drawer 41)
  - Kellogg, D. - Kellogg, S. (Drawer 42)
  - Kellogg, T. - Ladd (Drawer 43)
  - Lamphere - Little (Drawer 44)
  - Lombard - Lord, Q. (Drawer 45)
  - Lord, R. - MacGee (Drawer 46)
  - Mack - Merrell (Drawer 47)
  - Merritt - Morgan, S. (Drawer 48)
  - Morgan, T. - Niles, J. (Drawer 49)
  - Niles, J. - Olmsted, J. (Drawer 50)
  - Olmsted, K. - Packer, E. (Drawer 51)
  - Packer, F. - Patten (Drawer 52)
  - Patterson - Peters, N. (Drawer 53)
  - Peters, O. - Pomeroy, J. (Drawer 54)
  - Pomeroy, K. - Purcell (Drawer 55)
  - Purple - Ransom (Drawer 56)
  - Rathbone - Rockwell (Drawer 57)
  - Rogers - Rowley (Drawer 58)
  - Ruddan - Selby (Drawer 59)
  - Selden - Skinner, D. (Drawer 60)
  - Skinner, E. - Smith, R. (Drawer 61)
  - Smith, S. - Spencer, I. (Drawer 62)
  - Spencer, J. - Stark, H. (Drawer 63)
  - Stark, I. - Stocking, A. (Drawer 64)
  - Stocking, B. - Swan, B. (Drawer 65)
  - Swan, C. - Tarbox (Drawer 66)
  - Taylor - Tinker, R. (Drawer 67)
  - Tinker, S. - Turner (Drawer 68)
  - Turtlelott - Warner, H. (Drawer 69)
  - Warner, I. - Watrous, D. (Drawer 70)
  - Watrous, E. - Webster (Drawer 71)
  - Weeks - Wells, R. (Drawer 72)
  - Wells, S. - Wickwire, G. (Drawer 73)
  - Wickwire, H. - Williams, A. (Drawer 74)
  - Williams, B. - Williams, S. (Drawer 75)
  - Williams, T. - Worthington, K. (Drawer 76)
  - Worthington, L. - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 77)
- Inventory control book, 1721-1920; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1912-003
  Also known as the Godard Digest